John Rajan

Senior Front End Developer

Malaysia, Selandar

@ johnrajan95908@gmail.com

Phttps://github.com/JohnRajan95908

SUMMARY

Senior front-end developer with 7+ years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps in the financial industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Front End Developer

PandaBreak

= 2022 - 2023

Malaysia, Selandar

PandaBreak is a Sequoia-capital funded startup. Its contract management SaaS product modernizes the enterprise back-office.

- Created a custom client dashboard that reduced support tickets by 50%
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 25%
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems
- Presented findings in a clear and concise manner to key decision-makers

Front End Developer

Bouchard

= 2020 - 2022

Malaysia, Selandar

Bouchard is a residential real estate technology company launching their first app this summer. The app will allow consumers to see homes on demand via UBERlike technology. #SEEHOMESFAST

- Implemented performance tuning techniques on stored procedures and backend queries which resulted in 46% improvement in application performance
- I had the responsibility to train 4 people the front-end basics and helped them develop further
- Worked with an agile team of 12 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients

Junior Front End Developer

DocHub

= 2017 - 2020 Malaysia, Selandar

- Created 4 application to solve problems among the society
- Ensured end-to-end process of data extraction until reporting and noted efficiency of close to 25%
- Developed my team-work skills by working in close collaboration with 6 other students

EDUCATION

Degree of computer science

at Universiti Teknologi Malaysia

= 2013 - 2017

TECH STACK

Develop mobile applications

Design mockups and wireframes

Building APIs Elementor

Ruby **Ruby on Rails React Native Angular**

Git **jQuery** wordpress

LANGUAGES

React Redux

English

Fluent

Angular2

Malay

Native



TRAINING / COURSES

International Business

University of Stellenbosch Business School, 2018

Entrepreneurship & Innovation

University of California, Berkeley, 2018

CN Enhancy

EXPERIENCE

Junior Front-End Developer

Slickdeals

🗰 2017 - 2019 👂 Malaysia, Selandar

- Gathered requirements and assembled team of web developers and UX designers to build out new ticketing system, generating a scalable e-commerce platform that served millions of users per day
- Generated and implemented code for over 20 modules, including custom widgets and functionality to integrate third-party plug-ins for advanced analytics, data formatting, and multi-language support

PASSIONS

Competitive Gaming

Professional Club Debating